Dumidu **Handakumbura**



https://abuginthesystem.blogspot.com



BRIEF

As a skilled and highly educated professional with 8+ years of quality assurance experience I have had the opportunity of testing at all levels including, component, integration, system, and acceptance; both as a manual and automation tester.

Key Words: Manual Testing and SQE Process, Test automation, Web and API Performance Testing, Java, JavaScript, Python, Selenium, Cypress, REST-Assured, Linux, RDBMS, JMeter, GIT, Jira, IntelliJ Idea.



EDUCATION

MBA | Cardiff Metropolitan University, UK.

2021

BSc. Computer Science | Edith Cowan University, Australia. 2013



EXPERIENCE

Associate Tech Lead in QA | Sysco LABS

OCT 2018 - PRESENT

- Defined test strategies and test plans.
- Extracted test scenarios and designed test cases based on requirements.
- Executed test cases, analyzed results, created defect reports, and worked with the stakeholders to bring defects to resolution.
- Developed and maintained UI and API automation scripts.
- Developed and maintained data migration validation scripts.
- Developed and executed UI and API performance scripts.
- Reviewed code commits and helped maintain the automation code base.
- Configured and maintained CI/CD pipelines.
- Owned and drove testing related stories as a member of a geographically distributed Agile team. Completed a two-week on-site training (Houston, Tx).

Senior Software Engineer in QA | 99x Technology

JUN 2018 - OCT 2018

- Worked as part of a customer-facing agile team.
- Developed automation scripts using Protractor and JavaScript.

Senior Software Engineer in QA | Inova IT Systems

OCT 2017 – JUN 2018

- Assisted in daily maintenance and support activities related to a solution developed using WSO2 technologies.
- Derived test conditions from requirement documents and broke them down to test cases.
- Developed automation test cases using Java, Selenium, Maven, and TestNG.
- Helped develop a test framework.

Software Engineer in QA | WSO2

JAN 2014 - SEP 2017

- Designed test cases based on requirements and source code.
- Executed test cases, analyzed results, created defect reports, and worked with the stakeholders to bring them to resolution.
- Provided L1/L2 technical support to customers by engaging with them to troubleshoot issues and worked with the respective development teams to resolve the defect reports.
- Completed a 3-month onsite engagement where I used WSO2 products to create integration-related artifacts for a then ongoing digital transformation project at a reputed American establishment.
- Created test artifacts and contributed to internal QA tooling projects.
- Helped in knowledge retention and marketing through the creation of blog posts and publication of a white paper.

Technical Writer | Millennium IT

Feb 2010 – July 2013

- Developed technical documentation (User Manuals and Pre-sales content).
- Liaised with engineers and consultants to gather requirements to create the content.
- Managed and maintained product documentation.



STRENGTHS

- Attention to detail.
- Self Motivated.

- 8+ Years of SQE Experience.
- Loyalty.



OTHER

- Initiated an open source based project
 (https://github.com/handakumbura/Seleniumuntil) that can be used to improve selenium test automation readability, reduce code redundacy and provide features that reduce the need to write code from scratch.
- I am in the process of getting ISTQB certified.
- References can be provided upon request.